Wenqi Jiang Updated on 5/29/2022

# Wenqi Jiang

# Data Engineer / Backend Engineer

My name is Wenqi Jiang. I'm a software engineer with 3 years' experience in **big data** infrastructure and **backend** services, specializing in scalability, high availability, and low latency distributed systems design and implementation. I am proficient in Java and Scala.

Currently, I'm working with the Ontology Engineering Group (OEG) and studying for a master's degree in Data Science from the Polytechnic University of Madrid (UPM). In addition to my regular duties, I have learned to react and flutter for searching for new challenges.

#### **Contact:**

• Mobile: KzM0IDY5MS03NTItMTU3

• Email: jiangwenqi1995@gmail.com

Online Resume: jiangwenqi.infoGitHub: github.com/jiangwenqi

• Blog: dev.to/jiangwenqi

# Experience

OEG-UPM | Ontology Engineer

Dec. 2021 - Present

A student scholarship for the development of linking algorithms and graph linkers.

# LOOM-LD

- Analyzed ontologies from different data sources;
- Specialized 7 linking discovery algorithms, including text similarity and spatial relationships;
- Implemented a Sparql-based knowledge graph linker using customized Apache Jena functions;
- Evaluated those algorithms with OAEI-2021 datasets;
- Completed the master's thesis.

Keywords: Ontology Graph Linker RDF SPARQL Apache Jena Text Similarity DE-9IM WKT OAEI

TOGIC | Big Data Engineer

May 2019 - Aug. 2021 · 2 yrs 4 mos

#### **Offline Data Warehouse**

- Designed a STAR model Data Warehouse, which contained four-layer: ODS, DWD, DWS, and ADS, saving over 80% of storage and fixing small files' problems on HDFS;
- Developed and managed the Data Warehouse, which comprises over 150 tables and 200 TB of data, including user and system logs from Togic and Webox, producing 300 GB each day;
- Upgraded almost all big data components, including HDFS, Spark, Kafka etc.

Keywords: CDH Kafka HDFS HIVE Spark

# **Data Statistics System**

• Restructured the statistics system based on the new Offline Data Warehouse;

Wenqi Jiang Updated on 5/29/2022

• Rewrote the code by using DataFrame, making them more readable and maintainable, and reducing the process time to 25% compared to the previous one;

• Implemented more than 30 new statistical demands and fixed bugs.

Keywords: Sqoop Hive Spark SQL Scala Elasticsearch MySQL MongoDB

#### **Log Collection Service**

- Designed and implemented the log collection pipeline based on Nginx and Netty, improving performance and stability;
- Processed all logs into the message queues in Kafka, which has five brokers, three data backups, and seven days of log redundancy, improving the robustness of this service.

Keywords: Nginx Netty Java Kafka HDFS

# WEBSTUDIO | Backend Engineer

Jul. 2018 - Apr. 2019 · 10 mos

- Implemented backend APIs of big data visualization dashboards and general reports for the BI applications;
- Developed more than 25 data operators, such as summation, date conversion, string processing etc.;
- Implemented the one-click function of syncing all user information;
- Expanded 16 data sources, including MySQL, SQL Server, MongoDB etc.;
- · Maintained the big data platform;
- Fixed bugs and developed new features for the previous company's projects.

Keywords: Dubbo Spring Boot MyBatis Hibernate Nginx Docker FastDFS CDH HBase Impala

### KEG-THU | Software Engineering Intern

Feb. 2018 - Jul. 2018 · 6 mos

- · Organized and annotated critical illness insurance documents;
- Trained models to extract the logical structure of insurance documents by using GROBID;
- Created a desktop application using above models;
- Maintained datasets in NoSQL database, like MongoDB, Neo4j;
- Completed the thesis.

Keywords: NLP CRF GROBID Neo4j MongoDB Java FX

# **Open Source**

### Dapp Learning DAO

Apr. 2022 - Present

- Contributed various tutorial tasks;
- · Translated the basic tasks;
- Shared the latest blockchain news and cutting-edge technics in the community.

Keywords: Blockchain web3.js Solidity Dapp Ethereum Hardhat Alchemy Infura DAO.

# Education

- MS Data Science · Polytechnic University of Madrid | 2021 Present
- BE Computer Science & Technology · Beijing Information Science & Technology University | 2014 2018